

# PRADEEP MATHEW

DevOps Automation Engineer

## **PROFILE**

A seasoned IT professional based in Melbourne, Australia, with diverse experience in banking, consulting, insurance, retail, and entertainment industries in DevOps and Cloud Platform engineering.

I bring over 5 years of robust experience in cloud engineering and automation, primarily focusing on AWS and Azure-based workloads.

## CONTACT

PHONE:

+61 0415 250 136

WEBSITE:

https://pradeepmathewdev.com/

EMAIL:

pradeepishere2005@gmail.com

# **SKILLS**

Agile Methodologies Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)

Kubernetes

Bash

Buildkite

Codepipeline

SQL

**Docker Products** 

Jenkins

Azure DevOps

DevSecOps

Microservices

Microsoft Azure

Python

Linux

Terraform

ArgoCD

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Robotic Process Automation (RPA)

Release Management

Jira & Confluence

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MS University**

2000 - 2004

Bachelor of Engineering - Major-Computer Science

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AWS Solution Architect Associate
- AWS Cloud Practitioner
- GitOps Fundamentals
- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate
- Azure DevOps Engineer Expert
- Azure Administrator
- Azure Fundamentals
- ITIL 3&4 Foundation

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Tabcorp DevOps Automation Engineer-CI/CD

December 2021-Present

- Developed automation code for building CI/CD pipelines, Kubernetes clusters, and cloud infrastructure, embracing Agile methodologies.
- Led the deployment and management of a Java based real time transaction monitoring microservices application hosted on Kubernetes for Spring Racing Carnival.
- Automated HR recruitment workflow via UiPath Automation Suite.
- Integrated and managed SonarQube, Docker images, and GitHub for version control.
- Integrated and managed APM applications (New Relic, Splunk) for robust monitoring.
- Contributed to Java, Golang, and Python development, adept at debugging code-level issues.
- Actively participated in BAU application enhancements.
- Applied Terraform & CloudFormation for infrastructure provisioning.
- Managed Release and change for Automation & Engineering BU.
- Conducted thorough code reviews and sought DevSecOps opportunities for cost optimization in infrastructure and application code bases using Cloudconformity, Crowdstrike, Aqua, Snyk, and Billing dashboards.

# Coles Release Operations Environment Analyst

June 2018-November 2021

- Led Build and Deployment Insights data warehousing projects on Snowflake, PowerBI, Datafactory, ETL and Oracle.
- Collaborate with various projects for weekly twice code progression to production environments.
- Built and managed cloud resources on Azure Datafactory, Azure Pipelines, Azure Key vault, Azure AD, Storage and AKS.
- Developed automation scripts in Bash, Python, and PowerShell.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins and Azure DevOps, integrating Snowflake and PowerBI components seamlessly.
- Administered change/release records in ITSM tool (ServiceNow) and coordinated cross-team collaboration.
- Led cloud migrations, enhanced release processes, and advocated for DevOps practices, optimizing on-premises and cloud operations.

## IAG Environment Analyst

February 2014-May 2018

- Managed environment and code release deployments using build and automation tools.
- Set up lab environments for diverse projects, encompassing estimation, system design, development, and implementation.
- Led infrastructure and application upgrade projects, coordinating with vendors.
- SME of environment management team for Wesfarmers IAG Systems integration, Coles IAG systems integration, OpenText Capture systems and Adlib Application upgrade projects.
- Contributed to daily monitoring, maintenance, and patching of non-production server environments, and worked on cloud-based pipelines for document management solutions at IAG.

#### Capgemini Senior Consultant

September 2012-January 2014

- Effectively managed and resolved environmental support issues, addressing root causes and defects.
- Participated in regular, fast-track, and emergency releases, QA testing, business continuity testing, and vendor patch management.
- Collaborated closely with diverse teams, including testing, infrastructure, development, and release management.
- Served as the main point of contact for technical support issues related to servers, databases, debugging, and configurations within the Global Payments Applications team.
- Accomplished projects, including IBM Master Data Management implementation, Windows system upgrades, and a hardware refresh project for the Voucher Image 'Storage' System.

#### ANZ Technical Analyst

May 2006-August 2012

Worked as Test Environment management analyst across the major ANZ projects.

- Global Information Security team offshore setup and coordination
- PeopleSoft application setup and upgrade
- Global payments systems integration with PRIME regulatory systems
- Australia Post Forward Clearing Project
- Microsoft Reporting Services Application Upgrade Program
- CA Clarity v8 Application Upgrade Program
- PAYPLUS-FX online integration Program.
- Data Integrator Program (Royal Bank of Singapore IT merging with ANZ)
- PRIME Hardware/Application Refresh Program
- SUNCORP Bank Agency Clearing Project